<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-06-23T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Open Data - Tobin Bradley</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/06/23/open-data-tobin-bradley.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/06/23/open-data-tobin-bradley.html</id>
    <published>2014-06-23T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-25T23:36:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tobin is a GIS developer in Mecklenburg County.  He claims to "pretend" to develop software, but anybody who's got apps in production is a developer to us!  He is responsible for the first real open data in Mecklenburg County (and still the preponderance of county Open Data), available &lt;a href="http://maps.co.mecklenburg.nc.us/openmapping/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He provided &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/NjJXv2"&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of GIS-related open data tools and
then proceeded through a short training session.  Some of the information is
available at that link (which also allows for comments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will attempt to metion some additional data that came up during the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nconemap.com/"&gt;NC One Map&lt;/a&gt;: Twyla will be a good ambassador to
 the maintainers of this project.  I don't have the acronym handy, but she's
 part of the "GIS Council of Elders" that maintain this asset.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out OpenStreetMap's progression in Haiti after the earthquake there.
 &lt;a href="http://imgur.com/eYCJ08V"&gt;After earthquake&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://imgur.com/KuByKij"&gt;2 days later&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://imgur.com/3kzNhjn"&gt;3 weeks later&lt;/a&gt; – Open data saved lives in Haiti.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base maps and overlay are the components of geographic data.  The base maps
 are the images of the territory, and the affiliated data comprises the overlay.
 You probably only want to create base maps if you are a real pro.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The non-GIS specialists may want to pay special attention to &lt;a href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript library that supports geographic information presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tobin uses &lt;a href="http://geoserver.org/"&gt;GeoServer&lt;/a&gt; and Digital Ocean to serve "massive" GeoJSON / KML etc. representations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free accounts are available at ARCGis, Google, and MapBox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that data is half of the code/data battle!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
